

LOUIS PICARD

DIGITAL PROJECT MANAGER SELF-TAUGHT PROGRAMMER





CONTACT

louis-picard.com louis.picard01@gmail.com louis.picard@servier.com +33 7 82 69 11 89 +31 6 16 13 93 98

SKILLS

LANGUAGE SKILLS

French Native language English C1 Level Spanish C1 Level Dutch A2 Level A2 Level Portuguese

IT SKILLS

HTML5/CSS3/JavaScript Analytics 4 & GTM Wordpress/Woocommerce Design Photoshop/Canva Pack Office 360

DIPLOMAS

Certificaat Universiteit Leiden Nederlands A2 - 2021 TOEIC (915/980 points) - 2017 TOEFL (578/677 points) - 2015 DELE Cervantes (B2) - 2014

INTERNATIONAL **EXPERIENCES**

2020-2022

2 years expatriate in the Netherlands as V.I.E with the **Business France organization**

2017-2018

Semester in Rio de Janeiro (Brazil) at the Pontifical Catholic University

2012-2013

High School Year abroad in Formosa (Argentina) with the International Association AFS

ABOUT ME

Digital Project Manager with 3 years experience creating and maintaining functional, attractive and responsive websites. Clear understanding of modern technologies and best design practices. Experienced with Wordpress, Google Analytics and GTM. I want later on to become Web Developer as I am convinced it will better serve my career evolution interests.

EDUCATION

ESSCA BUSINESS SCHOOL OF MANAGEMENT

ESSCA - Paris 2014-2020

Master of Science degree Digital Marketing and Big Data for Value

EXPERIENCES

DIGITAL PROJECT MANAGER

SERVIER NEDERLAND, Leiden, June 2020 - May 2022

- Design and build website (Wordpress and Divi Builder), aligned with budget (12.000€)
- Monitor site load issue (score 87/100 on PageSpeedInsight), user traffic (+7,2k sessions and +2,5k unique visitors) and keywords performance (SEO) Analytics.
- Participating in omnichannel projects by developing better user tracking (+180 user accounts) via a tailormade data layer and tagging plan with Google Tag Manager and Analytics 4
- Working hand in hand with Marketing and KAM to create and implement content online (18 webinars, 27 podcasts/videocasts, 9 blog posts).

BRAND CONTENT & DIGITAL MARKETING ASSISTANT

LABORATOIRE GALLIA-DANONE ELN, Lyon, July 2019 - December 2019

- Manage Laboratoire Gallia's website: improving SEO, emailing operations with +1,6% OR, +0,7% of CTR on event NL
- Manage and organize the project activation with developpers team and graphic design and multimedia agency of a new brand identification on the website (template/reskinning of website front office), the app gMois&Moi and the automatic newsletter

WEBMARKETING ASSISTANT

DOMINO'S PIZZA FRANCE, Gennevilliers, January 2018 - August 2018

- Leverage on analytics tools to improve SEO, through the creation of landing pages to attract traffic while optimising for click-through rate.
- Setting up CRM campaigns (emailing, SMS, ...) using Selligent: creation of two lists (3 months participation and 6 months participation) which lead to an increase of +120.000 contacts in the database, +2% OR and +0,3% CTR in participation.
- Animation and coordination of partnership with the football league for Domino's Lique 2 (Facebook live, social media events and giveaway)
- Participation in the definition of the Social Media strategy and optimization of Community Management (+77K likes on Facebook, +850 followers on Instagram, +1,1K followers on Twitter).